League for Industrial Democracy Pamphlets 5266
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
League for Industrial Democracy Pamphlets
1905-1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
League for Industrial Democracy
5266
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Pamphlets.
Pamphlets from the League for Industrial Democracy
5621140
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 01, 2007
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 08, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Primarily a Socialist-oriented reform group.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
League for Industrial Democracy.; Abrams, Charles, 1902-1970; Alexander, Robert Jackson, 1918-; Alfred, Helen L.; Allen, Devere, 1891-1955; Barbash Jack; Barou, Noel; Bauer, John, b. 1881; Berube, Maurice R.; Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977; Blanshard, Paul, 1892-; Bloomberg, Warner; Brooks, Thomas R.; Chase, Stuart, 1888-; Clapp, Gordon R. (Gordon Rufus), 1905-1962; Cohen, Edward M.; Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953; Coldwell, M. J. (Major James), 1888-1974; Counts, George S. (George Sylvester), 1889-1974; Davis, Michael Marks, 1879-1971; Dewey, John; Douglas, T. C. (Thomas Clement), 1904-; Epstein, Abraham; Feldman, Sandra; Gaither, Thomas; Goldbloom, Maurice; Groseclose, Emmett; Harris, Seymour Edwin, 1897-; Herling, John; Shapiro, Morris; Hyman, Sonia Zunser; Ise, John; Kahn, Tom; Kingsbury, John Adams, 1876-1956; Laidler, Harry W. (Harry Wellington), 1884-1970.; Lane, Winthrop D. (Winthrop David), 1887-1962; Lash, Joseph P., 1909-1987; Lend, Evelyn; Levenstein, Aaron, 1910-; Lewis, Alfred Baker, 1897-; Lewisohn, Sam A. (Sam Adolph), b. 1884; Lindbom, Tage, 1909-; Lovett, Robert Morss; Maslow, Harold; Manson, Julius; Matthews, J. B. (Joseph Brown), 1894-1966; Meiklejohn, Kenneth; Nehemkis, Peter Raymond; Moe, Finn; Muste, A. J. (Abraham John), 1885-1967.; Nearing, Scott, 1883-; Neuman, Franz; Pell Orlie, 1900-; Perelman, Norman; Raushenbush, Carl; Raushenbush, Stephen, b.1896; Saposs, David J. (David Joseph), 1886-1968; Bliss, Elizabeth T.; Seidman, Joel; Senior, Clarence Ollson, 1903-1974; Sering, Paul; Soule, George; Starr, Mark, 1894-1985; Sutch, W. B., (William Ball), 1907-; Thomas, Norman; Ward, Harry Frederick, 1873-1966; Weisenburg, Mina; Withers, William, 1905-1987; Wolfson, Theresa, 1897-1972; Weiss, Abraham, 1913-; Young, Charles N.
5621140
- A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The Caribbean: Laboratory of World Cooperation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Devere Allen. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: L. I. D. 40th Anniversary, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By League for Industrial Democracy (LID). Item is in English.
  - Item 3: A Housing Program for America, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Charles Abrams. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: World Labor Today, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Robert J. Alexander. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Labor Parties of Latin America, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Municipal Housing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Helen L. Alfred. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: World Labor Today, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Robert J. Alexander. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: A Housing Program for America, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Charles Abrams. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Labor Parties of Latin America, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Robert Alexander. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Municipal Housing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Helen L. Alfred. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: The Caribbean: Laboratory of World Cooperation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Devere Allen. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- B [folder 1 of 2], Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
  - Item 1: Taft-Hartley Act In Action, 1947-1954 and Essentials of a New Labor Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Jack Barbash. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Recent Trends in British Trade Unionism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Noel Barou. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Americas Struggle for Electric Power, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By John Bauer. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Urban School Crisis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Maurice R. Berube; Nathan Glazer; Paul Goodman; Christopher Jencks; Jeremy Larner; Patricia Cayo Sexton; Irving Howe. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The Jewish Refugee Problem and The Egregious Gentile Called to Account, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Bruce Bliven; Grover C. Hall. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Labor in Southern Cotton Mills, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Paul Blanshard. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Technocracy And Socialism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
  - Item 8: The Age of Automation, Its Effects on Human Welfare, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Warner Bloomberg. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: British Labor on Reconstruction in War and Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Labour Party (Great Britain). Item is in English.
  - Item 10: To Build A New World, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Thomas R. Brooks. 30p. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Looking Forward: Discussion Outlines, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Jean Benson. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Work and Its Discontents, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Daniel Bell. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Americas Struggle for Electric Power, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By John Bauer. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Recent Trends in British Trade Unionism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Noel Barou. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Taft-Hartley Act In Action, 1947-1954 and Essentials of a New Labor Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Jack Barbash. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Labor in Southern Cotton Mills, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    By Paul Blanshard. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Technocracy And Socialism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
  - Item 18: British Labor on Reconstruction in War and Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    Copy 2. Item is in English.
- B [folder 2 of 2], Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 1: Taft-Hartley Act In Action, 1947-1954 and Essentials of a New Labor Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 2: Recent Trends in British Trade Unionism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 3: Americas Struggle for Electric Power, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 4: The Urban School Crisis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 5: The Jewish Refugee Problem and The Egregious Gentile Called to Account, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 6: Labor in Southern Cotton Mills, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 7: Technocracy And Socialism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 8: The Age of Automation, Its Effects on Human Welfare, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 9: British Labor on Reconstruction in War and Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 10: To Build A New World, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 11: Looking Forward: Discussion Outlines, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 12: Work and Its Discontents, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 13: Americas Struggle for Electric Power, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 14: Recent Trends in British Trade Unionism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 15: Taft-Hartley Act In Action, 1947-1954 and Essentials of a New Labor Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 16: Labor in Southern Cotton Mills, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 17: Technocracy And Socialism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  - Item 18: British Labor on Reconstruction in War and Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2b)
- C, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The Challenge of Waste, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Stuart Chase. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: One Billion Wild Horses, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Poor Old Competition, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Waste And the Machine Age, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Rich Land Poor Land, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Stuart Chase. From New Frontiers v.5:no.6 (1937:Sept.). 32pp. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: TVA and its Critics, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Gordon, R. Clapp. 14p. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Toward Independent Labor Politics in Britain, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Edward M. Cohen. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Immigration and National Welfare, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Felix S. Cohen. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Canadian Progressives On the march: The Story of the Rise of the C. C. F., Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By M. J. Coldwell. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: The Right to Make Mistakes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By George S. Counts. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: The Right to Make Mistakes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By George S. Counts. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Rich Land Poor Land, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Stuart Chase. L.I.D. Pamphlet Series. 27pp. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Canadian Progressives On the march: The Story of the Rise of the C. C. F., Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By M. J. Coldwell. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Canadian Progressives On the march: The Story of the Rise of the C. C. F., Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By M. J. Coldwell. Copy 2. Revised edition. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Toward Independent Labor Politics in Britain, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Edward M. Cohen. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: TVA and its Critics, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Gordon R. Clapp. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Canadian Progressives On the march: The Story of the Rise of the C. C. F., Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
- D, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: National Health Insurance: what is it? how would it work? why is it needed? alternatives?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Michael M. Davis. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Education and the Social Order, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By John Dewey. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Thirty-Five Years of Educational Pioneering and a Look Ahead, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By John Dewey; Norman Thomas; J. Daniels. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Canadians Find Security with Freedom, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Thomas C. Douglas. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Down on the Farm, the Plight of Agricultural Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Frank P. Graham. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Education and the Social Order, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By John Dewey. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Canadians Find Security with Freedom, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Thomas C. Douglas. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: National Health Insurance: what is it? how would it work? why is it needed? alternatives?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Michael M. Davis. Reprinted 1957. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Down on the Farm, the Plight of Agricultural Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Frank P. Graham. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: National Health Insurance: what is it? how would it work? why is it needed? alternatives?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Michael M. Davis. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: National Health Insurance: what is it? how would it work? why is it needed? alternatives?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Michael M. Davis. Copy 2. Reprinted 12957. Item is in English.
- E, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Economics of Defense and Reconstruction, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Old Age Security, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Abraham Epstein. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Old Age Security, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Abraham Epstein. revised. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Social Security, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Old Age Security, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Abraham Epstein. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Economics of Defense and Reconstruction, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By League for Industrial Democracy (LID). Copy 2. Item is in English.
- F, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Decentralization and the city schools, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Sandra Feldman. 14 p. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Forward March of American Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Freedom and the Welfare State: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Harry W. Laidler. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Forward March of American Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- G, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Strikes Under the New Deal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Maurice Goldbloom; John Herling; Joel Seidman; Elizabeth Yard; Joseph Schlossberg. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Subsidization of the Arts: a survey of governmental aid to music, art and the theatre in the free world, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Emmet Groseclose. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Strikes Under the New Deal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Maurice Goldbloom; John Herling; Joel Seidman; Elizabeth Yard; Joseph Schlossberg. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Strikes Under the New Deal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Maurice Goldbloom; John Herling; Joel Seidman; Elizabeth Yard; Joseph Schlossberg. Copy 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Jailed-In, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Thomas Gaither. Item is in English.
- H, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: National Health Insurance and alternative plans for financing health, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Seymour E. Harris. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Terzani Case, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By John Herling; Morris Shapiro. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Economic Security and World Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Sonia Zunser Hyman. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: National Health Insurance and alternative plans for financing health, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Seymour E. Harris. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Economic Security and World Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Sonia Zunser Hyman. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- I, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Our Vanishing Oil Resources, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By John Ise. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Our Vanishing Oil Resources, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By John Ise. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- J, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: John Dewey at Ninety, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By League for Industrial Democracy (LID). 37pp. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: John Dewey at Ninety, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By League for Industrial Democracy (LID). 37pp. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- K, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: The Problem of the New Left, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Tom Kahn. reprint. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Health Security for the Nation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By John A. Kingsbury. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The Economics of Equality, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Tom Kahn. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Health Security for the Nation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By John A. Kingsbury. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- L [folder 1 of 7], Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 1: Freedom and the Welfare State: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 2: Needed: A Moral Awakening in America: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 3: A Program for Labor And Progressives: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Stuart Chase; M. J. Coldwell. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: America in the Depression, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 5: British Labor as Government And as Opposition, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 6: British Labors Rise to Power, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 7: Consumers Cooperation; A Social Interpretation And the Consumers Cooperative Movement: A Factual Survey, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Laidler, Harry W; Wallace J. Campbell. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Federal Government And Functional Democracy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 9: How America Lives: A Handbook of Industrial Facts, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 10: How America Lives: A Handbook of Industrial Facts, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 11: Incentives Under Capitalism And Socialism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 12: Labor Governments at Work, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 13: Our Changing Industrial Incentives, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 14: Public Ownership Here And Abroad, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 15: Putting the Constitution to Work, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 16: Recent Developments in the American Labor Movement, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 17: The Role of the Races in Our Future Civilization, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Pearl S. Buck; Lin Yutang; Walter Nash; Norman Angell; Lawrence W. Cramer; T. T. Lew; Anup Singh; Walter White. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: Roads to Freedom, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 19: Socialism in the United States: A Brief History, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 20: The New Capitalism And the Socialist, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 21: The Third Freedom: Freedom From Want: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 22: Toward A Farmer-Labor Party, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 23: Toward Nationalization of Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 24: Unemployment And Its Remedies, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 25: Unemployment And Its Remedies, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 26: Unemployment Insurance Plans Abroad, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 27: World Cooperation And Social Progress: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Ralph J. Bunche; Paul H. Douglas; M. J. Coldwell; A. J. Hayes; H. L. Keenleyside; William Green; Selman A. Waksman; Raphael Lemkin; Paul R. Porter; Stanley H. Ruttenhouse. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: The Denial of Civil Liberties in the Coal Fields, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Winthrop D. Lane. Item is in English.
  - Item 29: The Campus Strikes Against War, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Joseph P. Lash. Item is in English.
  - Item 30: Karl Marx An Essay, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harold Laski. Item is in English.
  - Item 31: The Underground Struggle In Germany, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Evelyn Lend. Item is in English.
  - Item 32: The Atomic Age: suicide--slavery or social planning, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Aaron Levenstein. Item is in English.
  - Item 33: Why the C. I. O, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Alfred Baker Lewis. Item is in English.
  - Item 34: Labor, Machines And Depressions, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 35: Why We Have Depressions And Recessions, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 36: The Future of Capitalism and Socialism In America: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Sam A. Lewisohn; Scott Nearing; M. C. Rorty; Morris Hillquit. Item is in English.
  - Item 37: Swedens Labor Program, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Tage Lindbom. Item is in English.
  - Item 38: The Railroads Versus Public Interest, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Irving Lipkowitz. Item is in English.
  - Item 39: Monopoly And Big Business, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 40: Looking Forward: Discussion Outlines, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler. Democracy in Crisis. Item is in English.
  - Item 41: Maximum Production: Warfare and Welfare, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 42: The Middle Class and Organized Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Robert Morss Lovett. Item is in English.
  - Item 43: America in the Depression, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 44: British Labor as Government And as Opposition, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 45: British Labors Rise to Power, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 46: Freedom and the Welfare State: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 47: How America Lives: A Handbook of Industrial Facts, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 48: Incentives Under Capitalism And Socialism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 49: Labor Governments at Work, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 50: Maximum Production: Warfare and Welfare, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 51: Needed: A Moral Awakening in America: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 52: Needed: A Moral Awakening in America: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler. Copy 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 53: The New Capitalism And the Socialist, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 54: Our Changing Industrial Incentives, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 55: A Program for Labor And Progressives: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Stuart Chase; M. J. Coldwell. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 56: A Program for Labor And Progressives: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Stuart Chase; M. J. Coldwell. Copy 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 57: Public Ownership Here And Abroad, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 58: Recent Developments in the American Labor Movement, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 59: Recent Developments in the American Labor Movement, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 60: Roads to Freedom, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler. Third Edition. Item is in English.
  - Item 61: Socialism in the United States: A Brief History, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 62: The Third Freedom: Freedom From Want: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 63: Toward A Farmer-Labor Party, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 64: Toward Nationalization of Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 65: Unemployment And Its Remedies, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 66: Unemployment And Its Remedies, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 67: World Cooperation And Social Progress: A symposium, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harry W. Laidler; Ralph J. Bunche; Paul H. Douglas; M. J. Coldwell; A. J. Hayes; H. L. Keenleyside; William Green; Selman A. Waksman; Raphael Lemkin; Paul R. Porter; Stanley H. Ruttenhouse. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 68: Karl Marx An Essay, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Harold Laski. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 69: The Underground Struggle In Germany, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Evelyn Lend. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 70: The Atomic Age: suicide--slavery or social planning, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Aaron Levenstein. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 71: Why the C. I. O, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Alfred Baker Lewis. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 72: Why We Have Depressions And Recessions, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Item 73: Swedens Labor Program, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    By Tage Lindbom. Copy 2. Item is in English.